Bess Furman Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Bess Furman Papers 1728-1967 1900-1966
MSS21741
Furman, Bess, 1894-1969
47,000 items
155 containers plus 4 oversize
70 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Author and journalist. Correspondence, diaries, family papers, subject files, speeches and writings, financial records, scrapbooks, and miscellany relating primarily to Furman's family, personal life, and career as a journalist and author.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Aldrich, Bess Streeter, 1881-1954--Correspondence.; Armstrong, Robert Burns, 1903-1955. Robert Burns Armstrong papers.; Auerbach, Ella F.--Correspondence.; Enochs, Elisabeth Randolph Shirley, 1895-1992--Correspondence.; Furman family.; Furman, Bess, 1894-1969.; Furman, Lucile N., 1896-1961. Lucile N. Furman papers.; Helm, Edith Benham, 1874-1962--Correspondence.; Herrick, Genevieve Forbes--Correspondence.; Keyes, Frances Parkinson, 1885-1970--Correspondence.; Mason, Myrtle--Correspondence.; McAllister, Dorothy--Correspondence.; McBride, Mary Margaret, 1899- --Correspondence.; McCloskey, Iantha--Correspondence.; Netboy, Anthony--Correspondence.; Owen, Ruth Bryan, 1885-1954--Correspondence.; Rogers, Herbert H.--Correspondence.; Rogers, Mae--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962--Correspondence.; Thompson, Malvina, 1893-1953--Correspondence.; Truman, Bess Wallace--Correspondence.; Winslow family.
Organizations
American Association of University Women.; Associated Press.; Democratic National Committee (U.S.). Women's Division.; Furman Features.; League of Women Voters (U.S.); National Children's Bureau.; United States. Department of Health, Education, and Welfare.; White House (Washington, D.C.)
Subjects
American newspapers--Nebraska--Omaha.; American newspapers--New York (State)--New York.; Education.; Health.; Women.
Places
New Hampshire--Social life and customs.; Washington (D.C.)--Politics and government.; Washington (D.C.)--Social life and customs.
Titles
New York times.; Omaha bee-news.
Occupations
Authors.; Journalists.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Bess Furman, author and journalist, were given to the Library of Congress in several installments by Furman and her son, Robert F. Armstrong, between 1954 and 1969.
Transfers
Items have been transferred from the Manuscript Division to other custodial divisions of the Library. A painting by Ethel Evans, photographs, negatives, postcards, prints, and slides have been transferred to the Prints and Photographs Division. Books have been transferred to the Rare Book and Special Collections Division. Recordings and motion pictures have been transferred to the Motion Picture, Broadcasting, and Recorded Sound Division. Sheet music has been transferred to the Music Division. All transfers are identified in these divisions as part of the Bess Furman Papers.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Bess Furman are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1894, Dec. 2 Born, Danbury, Nebr.
1918 Graduated, Nebraska State Teachers College, Kearney, Nebr.
1918 1919 Staff writer, Kearny Daily Hub, Kearney, Nebr.
1919 1929 News feature and Sunday magazine writer, Omaha Bee-News
1929 1937 News staff reporter, Associated Press, Washington, D.C.
1932 Married Robert Burns Armstrong (died 1955)
1937 1941 Partner with her sister, Lucile N. Furman, in Furman Features, a press and radio consultant and writing service used especially by women's organizations
1941 1943 Assistant chief, Magazine Division, Office of War Information
1943 1961 Staff writer, New York Times
1949 Published Washington By-Line. New York: A. A. Knopf
1951 Published White House Profile. Indianapolis: Bobbs-Merrill
1962 Appointed head, press information section, Department of Health, Education and Welfare Published Progress in Prosthetics. Washington, D.C.: Office of Vocational Rehabilitation, U.S. Department of Heal, Education and Welfare
1969 Died, Woodacres, Md.
1973 Posthumous publication with Ralph C. Williams of A Profile of the United States Public Health Service, 1798-1948. Bethesda, Md.: National Institutes of Health
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Bess Furman (1895-1969) span the period 1728-1967, with the bulk of the material from 1900 to 1966. The collection focuses on the social and political events of the presidential administrations of Herbert Hoover, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Harry S. Truman, and Dwight D. Eisenhower. Furman's coverage of the activities of prominent women, especially first ladies, is well documented in the papers. The collection is organized in seven series: Diaries, Family Papers, General Correspondence, Subject File, Speeches and Writings File, Miscellany, and Oversize.
The diaries, 1924-1962, chronicle Furman's work as a writer for the Omaha Bee-News, Associated Press, and the New York Times. Her assignments took her from local events and personalities to the national and international scene. The earlier diaries contain personal comments on professional and family life; however, most of the diaries from 1944 to 1961 are comprised of clippings of precis of her articles. The last diary, 1961-1962, is a chronology of her activities at the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare.
A glimpse of Furman's personal life and Nebraska heritage can be seen in the Family Papers series, which spans the period circa 1728-1967. Material relating to her early forebears, the Winslow family of New Hampshire, includes correspondence, bills and receipts, bonds, deeds for property, and other items, particularly for Bartholomew Winslow and his wife, Hannah. Furman's connections with family are evident in copies of letters home that regularly appeared in the South Side Sentinel of Danbury, Nebraska, published by her father. In these letters Bess recounts her latest adventures "celebrity-chasing," as she called it. Also included in her family correspondence are "not for publication" personal opinions. Additional family material consists of the papers of her husband, journalist Robert Burns Armstrong (1903-1955), reporter for the Los Angeles Times, the Washington Post, and the St. Louis Globe-Democrat, and their children, Ruth Eleanor Armstrong and Robert Furman Armstrong, Jr.
Lucile N. Furman, Bess Furman's sister, came to live with the Armstrong family and together with Bess started a press and radio consultant and writing service called Furman Features that was used especially by national women's organizations. Material for this venture is available in the Family Papers, Subject File, and Speeches and Writings File. The Furman sisters wrote for such organizations as the Children's Bureau, the American Association of University Women, the League of Women Voters, and the Women's Division of the Democratic National Committee. They also wrote handbooks and campaign fliers for the Democratic National Committee.
The General Correspondence series, 1918-1965, is composed of incoming letters of both a personal and professional nature. They are from longtime family friends, journalists, first ladies, and professional contacts. Prominent correspondents include Bess Streeter Aldrich, Ella F. Auerbach, the Bobbs-Merrill Co., Elizabeth Randolph Shirley Enochs, Edith Benham Helm, Genevieve Forbes Herrick, Frances Parkinson Keys, Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., Dorothy McAllister, Mary Margaret McBride, Iantha McCloskey, Myrtle Mason, Anthony Netboy, Ruth Bryan Owen, Rohde, Herbert H. Rogers, Mae Rogers, Eleanor Roosevelt, Malvina Thompson, and Bess Wallace Truman.
The Subject File and Speeches and Writings File include research material, drafts of articles, and related correspondence, with emphasis on Furman's specialization in the areas of education, health, Washington social and political history, the White House, and women in public service.
In the Speeches and Writings File are extensive production materials for Furman's books: Washington By-Line, White House Profile, and A Profile of the United States Public Health Service, 1798-1948. There are also her reporter's notebooks and printed copies of newspaper articles from 1919 to 1960.
In the Miscellany series is a variety of material such as appointment books, clippings, financial papers, and invitations. Of particular interest are scrapbooks compiled by Furman and her family containing correspondence and clippings about her as well as articles written under the pseudonym, Bobbie O'Dare. Also in the series are scrapbooks of articles by Winifred Mallon, a predecessor on the staff of the New York Times, dating from 1903 to 1945. Other writings include manuscripts for books and articles sent to Bess and Lucile N. Furman for editing. Authors represented include Cecil Dickson, Elisabeth Randolph Shirley Enochs, Edith Nourse Rogers, and Fanny Jessop Sherman.
Organization of the Papers
The collection is arranged in seven series:
Diaries, 1924-1962
Family Papers, circa 1728-1967
General Correspondence, circa 1918-1965
Subject File, circa 1919-1960
Speeches and Writings File, circa 1919-1960
Miscellany, 1903-1966
Oversize
Container List
- Diaries, 1924-1962 (Box 1-6)
  Thirty-six volumes kept by Furman.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1924-1925, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - 1928
  - 1933-1938, (6 folders)
  - 1939-1944, (6 folders) (Box 2)
  - 1945, (2 vols.)
  - 1946-1948, (3 folders) (Box 3)
  - 1949, (2 vols.)
  - 1950, (2 vols.) (Box 4)
  - 1951, (2 vols.)
  - 1952
  - 1953-1954, (2 folders) (Box 5)
  - 1956-1959, (4 folders)
  - 1960 (Box 6)
  - 1961
  - 1961-1962 (HEW)
- Family Papers, circa 1728-1967 (Box 6-22)
  Correspondence of family members, condolence letters, birth and death certificates, memorial books, biographical material, financial papers, school papers, and other items.
  Arranged alphabetically by family member and then by type of material.
  - Armstrong family (Box 6)
    - Family manuscript (typed copy)
    - Armstrong-Furman marriage, 1932, (2 folders)
    - Armstrong, Blanche H., condolences on death, 1934 (Box 7)
    - Armstrong, Robert B., Sr.
      - Correspondence, 1928-1934
      - Estate, 1948-1949
      - Financial, circa 1928-1934
      - Letters of introduction, 1929
      - Miscellany
      - Sympathy notes and memorial book, 1946
    - Armstrong, Robert Burns (1903-1955)
      - Biographical information
      - Correspondence
        - Family
          - 1927-1949, (3 folders)
          - 1950-1954, undated, (2 folders) (Box 8)
        - General, 1928-1955, undated
      - Credentials
      - Desk calendars, 1933-1935, (3 vols.)
      - Insurance
      - Memorial book, 1955 (Box 9)
      - Miscellany See also Oversize, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 10)
      - Personal, circa 1932-1949
      - Refugee trip to Europe, 1948
      - St. Louis Globe-Democrat, circa 1944-1953
      - Sigma Delta Chi
      - War correspondent file, (2 folders) (Box 11)
      - Writings, (2 folders)
    - Ruth Eleanor and Robert Furman
      - Correspondence
        - Family, 1941-1964, undated
        - General, 1944-1963, undated
      - Miscellany
      - School paper, (4 folders) (Box 12)
  - Furman family (Box 13)
    - Furman, Archie C., 1926-1953, undated
    - Furman, Bess
      - Automobile accidents, 1965-1967
      - Biographical information, (2 folders)
      - Education (school grades and certificates)
      - Letters to family, 1930-1946, undated
      - Personal papers
        - 1937-1962, undated, (2 folders)
        - 1938-1965, undated, (3 folders) (Box 14)
      - School papers
      - Travel
    - Furman, Bess and Lucile N., Furman Features (joint venture), 1940-1942
    - Furman, Charles and family
      - Book business ( Washington-By-Line )
      - Correspondence
        - 1929-1959
        - 1961-1967, undated, (3 folders) (Box 15)
    - Furman, Donald A. and family
      - Correspondence
        - 1929-1965, (4 folders)
        - Undated (Box 16)
      - Memorial, 1965
    - Furman, Hazel Winslow
      - Correspondence, 1931-1950, undated
      - Miscellaneous
      - Writings and related correspondence, (5 folders); (7 folders) (Box 17)
    - Furman, Lucile N.
      - Biographical information
      - Correspondence, 1932-1961, undated
      - Financial papers
        - 1937-1941
        - 1942-1961, (8 folders) (Box 18)
      - Medical and insurance (Box 19)
      - Memorial book, 1961
      - Miscellaneous
      - Notes
      - Writings, (6 folders); (11 folders); (2 folders) (Box 20, Box 21)
    - Furman, Mattie
      - Condolences on death of, 1951, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1923-1950, undated
      - Miscellaneous
      - Memorial book, 1951 (Box 22)
    - Furman family miscellany
  - Hogan, Mabel
    - Financial papers, 1954-1961
    - Memorial book, 1960
  - Spencer, Annie Calvert
  - Van Pelt, Rollo W.
  - Winslow family papers, [1728?]-1863, undated, (2 folders)
- General Correspondence, circa 1918-1965 (Box 23-35)
  Letters received and a few letters sent primarily by Furman.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - "A" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box 23)
  - Abbott, Grace
  - Aldrich, Bess Streeter
  - Alfred A. Knopf See Container 28, Knopf
  - Angoff, Charles
  - Auerbach, Ella F. (Mrs. Herman H.)
  - Aves, Helen
  - "B" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
  - Banning, Margaret Culkin (Box 24)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Co., (3 folders)
  - Boettiger, Anna Roosevelt
  - Bugbee, Emma
  - "C" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
  - Coolidge, Grace Goodhe (Box 25)
  - Cowles, Gardner
  - Craig, May
  - "D" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
  - Dewson, Molly
  - Doebel, Naomi
  - Douglas, Helen Gahagan
  - Ducas, Dorothy
  - "E" miscellaneous
  - Edwards, India
  - Eisenhower, Mamie Doud
  - Enochs, Elizabeth Randolph Shirley
  - "F" miscellaneous
  - Farley, James A. and Elizabeth
  - Folsom, Marion B. (Box 26)
  - Funk, Ferne (Mrs. Wharton T.)
  - "G" miscellaneous
  - Garner, Ettie (Mrs. John Vance)
  - "Ha-Hoo" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
  - "Hop-Hy" miscellaneous (Box 27)
  - Hall, Mildred
  - Hayes Memorial Library, Fremont, Ohio
  - Helm, Edith
  - Herrick, Genevieve and John
  - Hickok, Lorena
  - Hobby, Oveta Culp
  - Hollenbeck, Don
  - Hoover, Don
  - Hoover, Herbert
  - "I" miscellaneous
  - "J" miscellaneous
  - "K" miscellaneous
  - Kennedy, Jacqueline
  - Keyes, Frances Parkinson (Box 28)
  - Knopf (Alfred A.) Inc.
  - Knopf, Blanche W.
  - Krock, Arthur
  - "L" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
  - Lamb, Howard E.
  - Lardner, Ring
  - Lehman, Herbert H.
  - Lennemann, Neta and William, (4 folders) (Box 29)
  - Lenroot, Katharine
  - Library of Congress
  - Lindsay, Malvina
  - "Ma" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
  - "Mc-My" miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 30)
  - McAllister, Dorothy and Thomas F.
  - McBride, Mary Margaret
  - McCloskey, Iantha
  - McCormick, Anne O'Hara
  - Mason, Myrtle (Mrs. Cyrus)
  - Meyer, Agnes Elizabeth Ernst
  - "Na-Ne" miscellaneous
  - "Ni-No" miscellaneous (Box 31)
  - National Concert and Artists Corp.
  - Netboy, Anthony
  - New York Times
  - Norton, Mary T.
  - "O" miscellaneous
  - Office for Emergency Management
  - O'Keefe, Georgia
  - Overlock, Dorothy
  - Owen, Ruth Bryan, (2 folders)
  - "P" miscellaneous (Box 32)
  - Park East
  - Perkins, Frances
  - Price, Bryon
  - Pringle, Henry P.
  - Puelz, Lelia
  - "Q" miscellaneous
  - "R" miscellaneous
  - Reston, James
  - Robison, Helen and Jesse N.
  - Rogers, Herbert H. and Mae
  - Rohde, Ruth Bryan Owen See Container 32, Owen, Ruth Bryan
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 33)
  - Ross, Ishbel
  - "S" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
  - Sanger, Margaret
  - Schwinner, Rosika
  - Sedgwick, Ellery
  - Skinner, Cornelia Otis
  - Strauss, Harold
  - "T" miscellaneous
  - Theta Sigma Phi (Box 34)
  - Truman, Bess Wallace
  - Truman, Harry S.
  - Truman, Margaret M.
  - "U" miscellaneous
  - "V" miscellaneous
  - "W" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
  - Webster, Margaret (Box 35)
  - Wei tao-ming
  - Wiley, Anna Kelton
  - Wilson, Edith Bolling Galt
  - Wylie, I. A. R.
  - "Y" miscellaneous
  - "Z" miscellaneous
  - Unidentified, (3 folders)
- Subject File, circa 1919-1960 (Box 36-63)
  Drafts of articles; research material, including notes, clippings, and printed matter; correspondence; and miscellaneous items.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Adams-Clement Collection, Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C. (Katharine McCook Knox) (Box 36)
  - Adolescent girls
  - Agriculture Department, (3 folders)
  - Aid to Dependent Children
  - Alexandria, Va.
  - Allergies and the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Disease
  - American Association of University Women, (2 folders)
  - American Council of Learned Societies (Box 37)
  - American Council on Education, Commission on Women
  - American National Red Cross
  - Anthony, Susan B.
  - Armed Forces Medical Library
  - Arthur, Chester Alan, (2 folders)
  - Artificial limbs
  - Arts
  - Association for Childhood Education International
  - Baldridge, Letitia
  - Baltimore schools, Baltimore, Md.
  - Barkley, Alben W.
  - Bequests to U.S.A.
  - Bills for the blind
  - Blair House, Washington, D.C., (4 folders)
  - B'nai B'rith
  - Borah, Mary (Mrs. William E.)
  - Chase, Agnes
  - Chiang, May-ling Soong
  - Children
  - Children's Bureau (Box 38)
  - Christ Church, Washington, D.C.
  - Church of the Epiphany, Washington, D.C.
  - Cigarettes and lung cancer
  - Communism
  - Cranberries
  - Daughters of the American Revolution
  - Decatur House, Washington, D.C., (2 folders)
  - Democratic National Convention, Philadelphia, Pa., 1936
  - Democratic Party (speeches)
  - Dewey, Frances (Mrs. Thomas E.) (Box 39)
  - Dewson, Mary W.
  - Dionne quintuplets
  - Displaced persons
  - D.C. Auditorium Commission, Washington, D.C.
  - Easter Seal Society and architectural barriers
  - Education, (3 folders)
  - Education
    - Federal aid to school construction
    - Four Track
    - In the USSR (Box 40)
  - Educational Policies Commission
  - Educational TV, Hagerstown, Md.
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., (2 folders)
  - Eisenhower, Mamie Doud, (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box 41)
  - Elizabeth II, Queen of England, (4 folders)
  - Engraving and Printing, Bureau of
  - Enochs, Elisabeth Randolph Shirley
  - Equal pay and equal rights
  - Fair trade legislation, (2 folders)
  - Farley, James A.
  - Federal Advisory Council on the Arts
  - Fine Arts bill
  - Flammable fabrics
  - Florida (Box 42)
  - Folger Shakespeare Library, Washington, D.C.
  - Folsom, Marion B.
  - Food and Drug Administration
  - Forand bill (aged)
  - Frederika, Queen of Greece
  - Front Royal, Va., children
  - Frost, Robert
  - Gallaudet College, Washington, D.C.
  - Garner, John Nance
  - General Federation of Women's Clubs
  - Greece
  - Haven-Simpson wedding
  - Health careers (Box 43)
  - Health, Education, and Welfare, Department of, (10 folders)
  - Health for Peace bill (Box 44)
  - Health insurance
  - Helm, Edith
  - Hill, Lister
  - Hobby, Oveta Culp
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell
  - Home economics
  - Hoover, Lou Henry
  - Housing
  - Howe, Louis M.
  - Humphrey, Muriel Buck
  - Ibarra, Jose Maria Velasco
  - Impacted areas laws
  - Inauguration, 1960
  - India
  - Infantile paralysis
  - Ives, Mrs. Ernest L.
  - Jackson Place, Washington, D.C., (2 folders)
  - Johnson, Louis
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., and family
  - Johnson, Lady Bird
  - Judaism (Box 45)
  - Juliana, Queen of the Netherlands, (2 folders)
  - Juvenile delinquency
  - Kennedy, Jacqueline, (2 folders)
  - Kennedy, John F.
  - Kennedy, Robert F.
  - Kerlan, Irvin, and the Kerlan Collection, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minn.
  - Khrushchev, Nikita Sergeevich
  - Land-grant colleges and universities centennial
  - Lapins
  - Leadbetter Drug Store, Alexandria, Va.
  - League of Women Voters, (2 folders)
  - Library of Congress
  - Library Services Act (Box 46)
  - Lincoln, Abraham
  - Lindbergh, Anne Morrow
  - Lindsay, Lady Elizabeth
  - Lobsenz Public Relations Co. (Amelia Lobsenz)
  - Loyalty oath
  - McAllister, Dorothy
  - McCarthy, Joseph A.
  - McCloskey, Dick
  - McLean, Evalyn Walsh
  - Margaret, Princess
  - Marriage and divorce
  - Medical Care Act
  - Medical history
  - Medicare program
  - Mental health
  - Mentally retarded
  - Monroe, James
  - Mutual Security Act of 1953
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People
  - National Defense Education Act (Box 47)
  - National Education Association
  - National Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs
  - National Health Council
  - National Health Survey
  - National Historical Publications Commission
  - National Institute of Mental Health
  - National Issues Committee (Eleanor Roosevelt)
  - National Trust for Historic Preservation
  - Nazi propaganda
  - Nebraska
  - Nebraska Psychiatric Institute, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 48)
  - Nebraska trip
  - Nixon, Pat
  - Nurses
  - Oettinger, Katharine Brownell
  - Office of Education
  - Office of Facts and Figures
  - Office of War Information, (5 folders); (2 folders) (Box 49)
  - Old age and survivors insurance
  - Oriental flu
  - Orr, Douglas
  - Owen, Ruth Bryan
  - Pandit, Vijayalakshmi
  - Parran, Thomas
  - Patent Office
  - Perkins, Frances
  - Personalities
  - Pierce, Franklin
  - Polio vaccine
  - Pollution, air and water
  - Population statistics
  - President's budget message, 1960
  - President's Committee on Education Beyond the High School
  - Presidential inaugurations
    - 1949
    - 1953, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 50)
    - 1957
  - Protocol
  - Public assistance
  - Public health
  - Public schools
  - Quezon, Manuel L.
  - Rambler (automobile)
  - Rayburn, Sam
  - Republican National Convention, Cleveland, Ohio, 1936
  - Reston, James
  - Retardation
  - Ribicoff, Abraham
  - Roche, Josephine
  - Rogers, Bruce
  - Rohde, Ruth Bryan Owen See Container 32, Owen, Ruth Bryan
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor
    - General, (3 folders); (10 folders) (Box 51)
    - Eleanor Roosevelt Golden Candlestick Award of the National Press Club, Washington, D.C.
    - Mrs. Roosevelt's Press Conference Association
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D.
    - General, (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 52)
    - Campaign, 1936, (2 folders)
    - Campaign literature, county fliers, (3 folders)
    - Family, (2 folders)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore (Box 53)
  - Royall, Ann
  - Russian education system
  - Russian embassy, Washington, D.C.
  - St. Elizabeth's Hospital, Washington, D.C.
  - St. John's Church, Washington, D.C.
  - Shipley, Ruth B.
  - Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C., (4 folders)
  - Social security
  - Society
  - Status Quo
  - Stevenson, Adlai (1900-1965) (Box 54)
  - Stough, Ada B.
  - Strayer, Martha
  - Subversive Activities Control Board
  - Surgeon General's display case
  - Taft, Robert A.
  - Teaching of Russian in United States schools
  - TV research
  - Thompson, Malvina
  - Ticks
  - Townsend, George A.
  - Truman, Bess Wallace, (6 folders)
  - Truman, Harry S., (4 folders)
  - Truman, Margaret, (4 folders) (Box 55)
  - Tuberculosis and isoniazid
  - Tyler, Julia
  - United Nations
  - United Nations International Children's Emergency Fund
  - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration, (8 folders)
  - United States Capitol Building, (3 folders) (Box 56)
  - United States Congress
  - United States Constitution
  - Unmarried mothers, (2 folders)
  - Vaccines
  - Venereal disease (Box 57)
  - Viet Nam
  - Vinnie's committee
  - Warm Springs, Ga.
  - Washington, George
  - Washington, D.C., (6 folders)
  - Washingtoniana shorts
  - Wei tao-ming
  - Welch, Henry, (8 folders) (Box 58)
  - White House